GRAHAM NESSLER

FRONT END SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Summary

I am a front-end software engineer with a focus on user experience and user interaction. In my prior career as a published historical scholar and educator, I learned the value of precision, analytical rigor, and adaptability to diverse learning styles and student needs. Now, I add value to organizations by combining these skills with knowledge of a variety of computer languages and technologies.

Projects

"Netwerker" (with Matt Kaufman and Christine Gamble)

Github Link

App Link

This is an app that stores network contacts. It allows the user to enter in info such as name, company, emails, social media, and notes. The user can also flag contacts for followup, delete contacts, and search contacts.

My core contributions: contributed several core features and some of the SASS/CSS styling.

React, SASS/CSS, Webpack, Enzyme, Mocha and Chai.

"Flash Shopper"

Github Link App Link

This is an independent solo project undertaken outside of the Turing School curriculum. It consists of a grocery list where users can enter in item name, aisle, quantity, and a note. Users can also choose a category (such as "Bread") from a dropdown menu, which will then populate the aisle number (this currently works only for my local King Sooper's, but I am hoping to expand this feature). The user can also sort items alphabetically and by aisle number and delete items. An edit feature is coming soon.

React, Firebase, JavaScript, SASS/CSS, Webpack

(For other projects, please see my projects website).

Experience

Florida Atlantic University Visiting Professor of History

Boca Raton, FL Aug 2015 to May 2016, Aug 2015 to May 2016

· Taught courses in United States, Caribbean, Latin American, and global history to around 200 students

Bentley University

Post-Doctoral Fellow

Waltham MA

Sep 2013 to Jul 2015

· Completed book manuscript

· Taught an undergraduate course on dictatorships in modern Latin America

Texas A&M University--Commerce

Ad Interim Assistant Professor of History

Commerce, TX Aug 2012 to May 2013, Aug 2012 to May 2013

• Taught courses in United States and Latin American history at both the graduate and undergraduate levels

Other Interests

Author

Author of book entitled An Islandwide Struggle for Freedom

Revolution, Emancipation, and Reenslavement in Hispaniola, 1789-1809 (University of North Carolina Press, 2016)

Black Belt in Taekwondo

Received in 1995 at Brian Rogers Taekwondo studio, Bryan, Texas.

Contact

http://www.grahamnessler.com/

(215) 804-7381 (USA)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/grahamnessler-b9025756

? gness1804

Skills

CORE TECHNICAL TOOLBOX

JavaScript/ES6

React/React Router

Redux

Ember jQuery

JSON and Ajax

Agile/Pair Programming

CSS/SASS

HTML5 Canvas

TDD HTML5

Firebase

Git/Github

Webpack

Vim

Enzyme and Selenium

Mocha and Chai

Swift

ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES

Sketch

Atom. Sublime Text

FileMaker

Microsoft Office

Blackboard

i-clickers

Pearson eCollege

Turnitin

NON-TECHNICAL SKILLS

Excellent writing skills

Proficient in Spanish, French, and English

Working knowledge of Brazilian Portuguese

Mentoring and leadership

Teaching and public speaking

Teamwork and group collaboration

Education

Turing School of Software and Design Certificate in Front End Engineering 2017

University of Michigan PhD History 2011

College of William and Mary **BA History 2005**